[bell]
>> This is my everyday.
Pretty much.
>> [music]
>> I wake up early and only spend the first
hour of the day doing absolutely
nothing.
>> [music]
>> I I don't know why, but
I always shave before I run.
Time to wake up for school.
Time to wake up.
Then I shower.
>> [music]
>> My daughter's shower to-do list.
[music]
>> How do you get this stuff?
>> [music]
[music]
>> Tiny pancakes, grapes, watermelon.
Girls, come out for breakfast.
>> [music]
>> Kids off to school, then work.
This is the crux of my day, the
productivity matrix.
>> [music]
>> The matrix is delineated by quadrants
with the Y axis representing
productivity, productive, unproductive,
and the X axis representing how much I
want to do the thing.
I want to do it.
I don't want [music] to do it.
The red quadrant comprises things I want
to do but should absolutely not do.
>> [music]
>> Red quadrant activities aren't just
unproductive.
They're counterproductive.
>> [music]
>> They're the opposite of work.
The enemy of work.
Yo. But they're fun.
They're the sirens calling out to me
anytime I approach productivity.
They're always there and I always want
to do them.
Juxtaposing red is green. These are the
things I want to do
>> [music]
>> and absolutely should do
but for some reason I avoid doing.
I enjoy these things, yet
>> [music]
>> I avoid these things.
The yellow and blue quadrants are
secondary.
They don't define the productivity
conflict, but they do contribute to it.
>> [music]
>> Things I don't want to do but absolutely
need to do.
Sorry for the delay in getting back to
you.
>> They're important
and productive,
but they always feel like a waste of
time.
Things I don't want to do and don't need
to do but will do to avoid doing the
things I should do.
This is the apex of procrastination
matrix.
These things don't need to be done,
[music] but while doing them, I can tell
myself I'm doing something that needs to
be done. When in reality, I'm just
avoiding the thing I should be doing.
>> [music]
>> I catch myself doing things that I'm not
supposed to do.
Some people are motivated by like
success and being like the feeling of
getting it done and feeling like they
accomplished something and that's
awesome and they did it. Mine was like
I'm going to finish this paper because
if I don't, I'm going to fail.
So, Candace is motivated by a fear of
failure. I I don't feel that way at all.
I don't
I don't feel like motivation is the
issue, but I I still feel I feel like
I feel I still feel like my everyday
everyday feels like it's mostly the
things [music] that I don't want to do,
but I have to do.
And then a lot of things that I don't
necessarily have to do, but I I do. And
then a good percentage of things that I
don't need [music] to do, but I like to
do. And then some itty-bitty percentage
of the things that I like to do and I
want to do.
This is my day. This is what every
everyday feels like. I don't like this.
The killer
Uh the secret the secret is waking up
late
and working cuz I can't really start
working until like 4:30. And you have
like
>> When everyone kind of starts to go home,
then things get quiet and I like to work
until like 2:00 in the morning. Okay.
>> So, that's part of That's That's most of
it.
Max Max has a point. See,
when my brother Ben and I, this is Ben,
this is Ben here, that's me there, when
Ben and I were making our what became
our HBO show way back in the day, we had
a rule and the rule was that
like after [snorts] hours no one was
allowed to come to the studio, no one
was allowed to come bother us because
when you work super late, like the phone
stops ringing, you stop getting emails,
everyone leaves you alone. And because
you're at the office late, you don't
dilly dally because you're like if I'm
going to waste time, I'll just go home.
So, you're focused. All of this goes
away and it's just this. But,
I got kids, man. I go home early. This
doesn't work for me. Max, I know you
procrastinate.
>> I do procrastinate a lot.
Um, I browse Twitter for like 15 minutes
and then I take a pause. I work for 2
minutes and then browse Twitter again.
Not helpful, Sam. See, when I'm having
trouble finding clarity in something,
when I can't make sense of something,
sometimes I'll write it down and
sometimes I'll make a video about it.
And this video is about how every day
feels like a negotiation
with the Matrix. And I was looking
for clarity as to why every day
feels like this. And I think that
clarity lies right right here.
Feels. I am productive. I get stuff
done. I get all this done, but it
it feels like I don't get anything done
because
I need candy.
>> [music]
[music]
>> It feels like I don't get anything done
because no matter how much of this work
or this work or this work I do, it
doesn't accumulate. I have nothing to
show for it.
There's
busy work and then there's like
productive work and the delta between
total procrastination and busy [music]
work, it's it's mushy. At times busy
work can feel like procrastination and
at times procrastination can feel like
busy work, but productive work here,
this is absolute. This is tangible. This
leaves you with something.
And for me as a creator,
these are videos. [music]
Every time I finish a video, I can look
back and it's it's right here. I I did
it. These don't go [music] away. Instead
of instead of leaving work thinking
about how many phone calls I did or or
how much cleaning I got done or how much
time I just wasted, I go home knowing I
finished the thing that day.
And that's
that's the clarity. That's the takeaway.
Regardless of what the endeavor is,
regardless of what the the output is,
whether it's professional or personal,
this is all unavoidable. This is what's
necessary in order to do this. You have
to navigate the storm before the ship
can be brought in.
>> [music]
[music]
>> And that
that is what my everyday looks like.
>> Yeah.